ANDREA MAZZEO

SOFTWARE ENGINEER



Pollate, Milan, Italy

28 September 1995

andrea.mazzeo95@gmail.com

+39 3498664241

https://andreamazzeo289.github.io

in www.linkedin.com/in/andreamazzeo289

HARD SKILLS

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

C, C++, QT, PYTHON, GIT, JIRA

COMPUTER VISION

OPENCV, DEEP LEARNING, PYTORCH, KERAS, TENSORFLOW

EMBEDDED SYSTEMS

FPGA, VHDL, VERILOG

WEB DEVELOPMENT

JAVASCRIPT, HTML, CSS

SOFT SKILLS

TEAM WORK
PROBLEM SOLVING
COMMUNICATION
AUTONOMY
TIME MANAGEMENT
ADAPTABILITY
LEADERSHIP

LANGUAGES

ITALIAN • • • • •

ENGLISH • • • • •

PROFILE

Versatile software engineer highly involved in research activities concerning computer vision and deep learning world. Always been passionate about low-level programming, where attention to detail is key. I'm willing to learn and improve with new challenging experiences.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | SMART ROBOTS | 2021 - PRESENT

MAIN ACTIVITIES:

C++, CMake, QT, OpenCV, Computer Vision

TEACHING ASSISTANT | POLITECNICO DI MILANO | 2020 - 2021

COURSE:

Fondamenti di Informatica

RESEARCH GRANT | POLITECNICO DI MILANO | 2020 - 2021

RESEARCH TITLE:

Design and analysis of image processing applications for critical systems

EDUCATION

MASTER'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING | 2017 - 2019

POLITECNICO DI MILANO

110 with honors / 110

THESIS

A Hybrid Fault Injection Framework for Image Processing Applications in FPGA

AREAS OF INTEREST:

Image processing and computer vision, embedded systems, firmware development, reconfigurable devices, computer architectures

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING | 2014 - 2017

POLITECNICO DI MILANO

105 / 110

FINAL PROJECT:

Lorenzo il Magnifico – A multiplayer board games developed in Java

AREAS OF INTEREST:

Software engineering, full stack development, networking, database design

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA IN ELECTRONICS AND IT ENGINEERING | 2009 - 2014

ITCS ERASMO DA ROTTERDAM, BOLLATE

98 / 100

FINAL PROJECT:

A tracking system of an object using a CCD sensor

AREAS OF INTEREST:

FPGA, microcontroller ARM, robotics, PCB design

PUBBLICATIONS

USABILITY-BASED CROSS-LAYER RELIABILITY EVALUATION OF IMAGE PROCESSING APPLICATIONS

IEEE INTERNATIONAL SYMPOSIUM ON DEFECT AND FAULT TOLERANCE IN VLSI SYSTEMS 2021
C. Bolchini, L. Cassano, A. Mazzeo, A. Miele

APPROXIMATION-BASED FAULT-TOLERANCE IN IMAGE PROCESSING APPLICATIONS

IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON EMERGING TOPICS IN COMPUTING | 2021

M. Biasielli, C. Bolchini, L. Cassano, A. Mazzeo, A. Miele

ERROR MODELLING FOR IMAGE PROCESSING FILTERS ACCELERATED ONTO SRAM-BASED FPGAS

IEEE INTERNATIONAL SYMPSOSIUM ON ON-LINE TESTING AND ROBUST SYSTEM DESIGN | 2020

C. Bolchini, L. Cassano, A. Mazzeo, A. Miele